Shit!
Eren, you're awake?
Just hang in there a while
longer. Everything's fine.
Historia's all right?
Eren, listen to me.
My father has been an ally to
all of humanity within the walls,
for many years past and many years to come.
We were clearly mistaken about him.
It's true that he's been a
problem for the Scouts,
and his people did
kill Pastor Nick...
But he didn't have any other choice.
Everything he's done, he had
to do for the sake of humanity.
Historia. Let me explain the rest.
It's coming back to me... Yeah...
The last thing I can remember is those two.
How long has it been?
Captain... Armin...
What happened to the Scouts?
What's up with these walls,
glowing like that...?
I can't tell if it's day or night...
No, hold on a second...
Haven't I been to this place before?
What's wrong? This is the first
time you've come here.
Though, it wouldn't be strange
if you recognize it.
What does he mean by that?
F-Father, explain to Eren.
Yes, I intend to.
However, there's something
I want to try first.
If we do this, he may
remember all on his own.
What... is this?
These aren't things I've seen...
No!
Whose memories are these?!
This key!
Is this...?
It can't be...
Dad?
Well?
Did you remember? Your father's sin...
"Sin"
You're amazing, Historia!
Look at how well you can read now!
That's only because you taught me so much!
Hey, we can't have this.
You've got a runny nose.
You need to learn to be
more ladylike, Historia.
Here, blow.
Ooh!
Good! Very well done!
Hey.
Hmm?
What does being ladylike mean?
Well... I suppose being ladylike means
being a lot like this girl right here.
Christa?
Right. You like Christa, too,
don't you, Historia?
Yeah.
Christa is always thinking about
other people because she's so kind.
You should try to be like Christa, too.
The world is full of pain and suffering,
so you should live in a way to be
helpful and loved by everybody.
Okay.
In that case, I wanna be like you.
Huh?
When I grow up, do you think
I can be just like you?
Sure!
Whoa!
Sure, sure! That's perfectly fine!
Whoa...
I'm sorry, Historia, but
it's time for me to go.
You'll have to forget about me again.
Until we can meet again.
Huh?
Huh? Who was that girl just now?
What's wrong, Historia?
Why?
Why did I forget about that until now?
I was never alone.
That girl was always there for me.
She gave me books...
Taught me how to read and write...
And was so kind to me...
How could I forget about her?
You met Frieda?
Frieda?
If it was a young girl
with long, black hair...
it was most likely Frieda Reiss.
She was your half-sister.
She must have been worried and
came to check up on you occasionally.
If she was erasing your memories,
it was all done to protect you.
Huh? Erasing my memories?
Yes, but touching your
hand to him seems to have
uncovered those memories again.
Um, Father?
Where is Frieda at now?
I'd like to see and thank her.
If she wasn't there for me, I...
I need to thank her for
what she did for me then.
Frieda is no longer in this world.
Huh?
At one time, I had five children.
But my wife and all of my
children, Frieda included,
were killed five years ago
by his father, Grisha Jaeger.
Grisha was a person with
the Power of the Titans.
I do not know who the man was, but...
...his goal was to steal the power
the Reiss family possessed.
This power Grisha sought to obtain...
It was the Power of the Titans
residing within Frieda.
Frieda's Titan was superior
to all other Titans.
You could say her Titan
had unsurpassable power.
However... She did not have
the experience to properly wield it.
Unable to unleash her true potential,
she was eaten by Grisha
and he stole the power.
But that's not all...
He then attacked my entire family.
His rampage sought to
eradicate the Reiss family.
He crushed the 14-year-old Dirk
and 12-year-old Abel.
He trampled over my wife and 10-year-old
Florian still clutched in her arms.
Lastly, he took my eldest son, Ulklin,
and squeezed the life out of him.
Miraculously, I was the only
one who made it away.
Unbelievable...
That's how she...
Why would he do such a terrible thing?
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
What the hell are you guys
blabbering about in here?
I hope you know a buncha shit
is going down outside.
Kenny? What happened?
The Scouts started a coup d'etat
and all the regiments changed sides.
Everyone knows the King's a big fake,
and all the big shots
ended up getting captured.
Oh yeah, it's a royal shit show.
Only a matter of time
till they show up here.
You oughta wrap it up lickety split.
Yes, all right.
Take your Anti-Personnel Control
Squad and defend the entrance.
I believe I told you already that
I need you and your crew
to leave for the ceremony.
Whoa, now, King. Did I make you mad?
Sorry 'bout that. I'm just
so worried about you.
Kenny... I trust you. Go.
So do I, King.
Tsk.
From now on, you'll be digesting
everything you eat from the bottom up.
Plus, the only clothes you get to wear
start at your knees and below.
Of course, once a week
we'll take you outside
and parade you around
to the public.
How beautiful...
This may very well be the finest
work of art ever conceived.
All those decades I spent
envisioning it paid off.
But see, only after you're
publicly humiliated
in front of the same
people you tyrannized
will this masterpiece be truly complete.
Zachary!
You just wait and see!
The only blood in you is slave blood!
It's nothing like our noble bloodlines!
Soon enough, you'll lose your memory
and even forget how to shit!
That one insult of yours
is getting pretty stale!
Don't you have anything new?!
This could be bad, Erwin.
All the officials are
saying similar things.
It's just as your father speculated.
The Reiss family must be able to alter
people's memories as it suits them.
From the sound of it,
certain bloodlines,
including theirs, are
immune to the effects.
How is that even...?
If Reiss is able to
obtain Eren's "Scream,"
this uprising will amount
to absolutely nothing.
As proof of that, they're spilling
all their secrets with no shame.
As if saying we'll get what's coming to us.
I see...
In other words, we may forget
even that fact altogether.
Though, I suppose having them
experience torture by the hands of Zachary
is better than nothing in my book.
I don't understand that man.
To think he dedicated so much
of his life just so he could do that.
Commander, you knew about him?
Mmm... 'Twas a slip of the tongue.
Indeed...
I suspected Dhalis Zachary
had such ambitions.
Unlike you, I'm not very fond of gambling.
And also, unlike you...
...I value the number of remaining
humans over my own life.
The reason I backed you
was because I believed
it the superior
choice for humanity.
Had the government been
the favorable choice,
I was prepared to fight against Zachary.
To think, we're comrades just following
a coup d'etat, and look what I'm saying...
I once heard a song that someday humans
will stop fighting, but when will that be?
Commander!
All troops are prepared and ready!
We're ready to go!
Humans will continue to fight one another
until the day there's one human or less.
I was hoping for a better answer
than some bleak hyperbole.
All troops, fall in!
Our mission to recover Eren
and Historia will now commence!
We make for their location, believed
to be the chapel on Reiss territory!
Understand?
He's Kenny the Ripper.
If he's there, he'll be
our biggest obstacle.
In terms of how much of a threat he is,
equate him to me as an enemy.
No... With those weapons of his,
he's deadlier than me.
Then he's unbeatable, at least for us...
If we could meet up with the troops...
Absolutely not.
I know, absolutely not!
If we wait until morning, Eren
might end up getting eaten!
Though, if what the captain said is true,
it's not like he has no weak points.
For real, Armin?
Yeah, I'm sure he's trained plenty, but
having combat experience is something else.
I wonder, how is it that you
lived with Kenny the Ripper
but know almost nothing about him, Levi?
Sorry, but I only found out
his full name not too long ago.
Apparently, it's Kenny Ackermann.
He some relative of yours?
I heard from my parents when they were
alive that my dad's side, the Ackermanns,
were persecuted in the cities.
My mom's family was Oriental,
so being a different race meant
they didn't fit in anywhere.
Both were people chased deep in the
mountains near the edge of the walls,
so that's how they met and married.
But I never found out why the
Ackermanns were persecuted.
My dad didn't seem like a
different race like my mom was.
Has there ever been a moment
where it's felt like power
suddenly awakened inside you?
There has.
Kenny Ackermann had a
moment like that, too.
One time, out of nowhere,
he felt an absurd amount of
strength surging within him
and he knew exactly what he had to do.
I've felt moments like that, too.
Fess up, Gramps.
You're about to die anyways, right?
Kenny...
Were you out killing more Military Police?
Yeah...
If you're talking about
those goons snooping around,
they're in the ground
helping the trees grow.
Speaking of branches,
the branch family moved down
south around Shiganshina.
But it turns out someone's interfering
with their business there, too,
so they're still poor as hell.
What's the big deal?
Didn't the Ackermanns use to be a
family of warriors protecting the King?
Now the whole family is on
the verge of extinction.
The hell did you do to
piss off the King so much?
C'mon, fess up.
Wontcha tell your cute grandson?
What cute grandson?
The one who's Kenny the Ripper,
terror of the capital?
The Ackermann family
isn't hated by the King.
It's just, they're afraid of us.
It's because the King isn't able
to control the Ackermann family.
Control?
I personally don't know
all there is to know.
But it's true that our
family was once the
King's sword and one of
their vital supporters.
However, the King passes down the Power of
the Titans from generation to generation.
Huh? What's this Power of the Titans?
It's an immense power they possess
to alter all of humanity's memories
and make them entirely forget the past.
Except for a few noble bloodlines.
Among them, there were two groups
that turned their back on the King.
That is, the Oriental clan
and the Ackermann family.
Hence the persecution.
Such a dreadful story.
It ain't the heartwarming story
you wanna hear on your deathbed,
but I did find my little sister.
Kuchel's been working at
a brothel in the underground.
Got pregnant by one of her customers.
Wants to have it and won't listen to me.
Hell...
Being born in this piece of shit world...
Ain't a single damn dream
worth suffering through it.
Found it.
A hidden door.
Eren's gotta be in here with the enemy.
Hopefully the layout in
there is like I predicted.
These presents better pay off, considering
we went out of the way to prepare them.
There's seven enemies at the least.
You can be sure Levi's among them.
As you know, Levi got completely
ambushed last time
and yet he still killed 12 of our comrades.
The rest of the Interior Police
are out of the picture,
not to mention the government lost control.
It's a bad situation all around.
In a world as tiny as ours,
dying would be preferable to the life
that awaits us the second we surrender.
Then again, is a life stuck
in these walls any different?
We've got an enemy we can't defeat
and all we can do is wait
till they break down the
walls and destroy us.
We chose to join the Military Police,
aspired to be Interior Police,
and joined up with Kenny.
All to seek meaning in our meaningless
lives in this meaningless world.
Let's keep believing all
the way to the end...
...that Kenny and his dream can
turn the tables on this world.
All right, we're good to go!
Are we?
Is everyone ready to get
their hands dirty, too?
Guess so.
To protect his wish...
To rescue him...
To carry on his memories...
Their many feelings lead
straight towards battle.
Next episode: "Wish."
"Wish"